[Music]
Hello and thank you for joining. I
wanted to share about some personal
story. I needed a cable. Sometimes you
need cable pretty urgent. I drove to a
couple of stores and there is nothing
but uh online you can buy them and get
them in couple of days but I needed
cable right now. Uh so end up buying two
cables and connected them to each other.
That hurts my feelings. But what this
story tells us just one of examples when
people
me in this case prefer to do inerson
inerson shopping for different reasons.
Maybe they needed something right now.
Maybe they prefer to try things out.
Maybe they want to consult with a person
to get a professional advice. But in
person sales still exist.
Uh so and Shopify also provides a
solution
for this case. It's called Shopify POS
point of sale which allows people in
store to perform transactions uh and uh
accept payments from other customers.
All right. Here I'm using the very basic
version. It's a app which I installed on
my phone and uh I can configure the
different uh action styles on top of it
and can create the simple thing as a as
a transaction. So I'm selling to
specific customers some specific item
and I'm ready to go to checkout. Of
course there are more advanced versions
including hardware and integration to
payment providers etc.
So all transactions sales transactions
performed on Shopify POS are integrated
into Shopify admin store as a normal
sales order. So you can see them uh in
the full list of orders among uh orders
placed via online store or other
channels and it is as other uh normal
orders will be imported into the
business central. But there are a couple
of nuances related to orders created via
POS. First, in some countries there is a
rounding uh related to the cash
transactions. We will talk about it. And
another one is like usually there is a
person who performs a sales transaction.
So you want to track your employees
performance and see like who is doing
most of the sales and registering them.
So let's go to the demos and see it. But
before going to the demo, I will show
you something. We are shooting this
video in Denmark. And this is the
smallest available Danish coin. It's a
half of the corona. All right. So this
is like what the smallest one one you
can use if you pay in person using cash.
But you still see the these kind of
prices 75 95 95 95 pls very it's okay if
you pay with a credit card but it's if
you're paying with a cash something will
happen what is it rounding up or down
depends on the amount and Shopify post
uh does that automatically not only in
Denmark but in other countries where the
situation is similar for example Canada
Uh and now we can import this
information into the business central.
All right, let's uh sell something and
see how it works. All right, we already
started to play with the Shopify POS and
created a draft orders. So for some
customers, some chair and amount is uh
40. I still cannot pronounce this uh
this uh coin name. Let's move to check
out. Now I can pay in different payment
methods. Uh I don't have any credit card
integration configured in this store.
Notice as soon as I press cash the
amount has changed. So now it is not 40
but 50. All right let's press it
and we're done. Check out is completed.
Shall we open it in Business Central?
Before we open business center, let's
have a quick look at the order uh placed
order in the Shopify admin. Yeah, you
can see it looks uh familiar. Looks the
same as a normal order. The only
difference is you can see the line which
says cash rounding. I'm in business
central. I will click Shopify shops and
apparently I was preparing for other
videos as well and created multiple
stores here. Let's take a look at this
one. Uh let's activate it
and navigate to list of orders.
Right.
Sync order. We are going to import all
orders.
I have couple of POSOS orders from the
same customer. Uh let's open the last
one which we just created together with
you. So we can see SW channel customer
and amount. There is a new field which
is called payment routing amount. All
right. And now what we plan to do, we
plan to create sales document
because it's already uh paid and uh
fulfilled. Then it will be created as
invoice. But not that fast. Apparently
something is missing. You can see the
error message which says cash rounding
account is missing. Correct. We need to
put this difference somewhere. So let's
go back to the uh Shopify shop.
and review which setups are missing.
There is a new field on the order
synchronization and processing tab.
I created account and I just decided to
call it rounding because we can create
any account we want in the business
central. Now I have my account defined
and
let's try again. Create sales document.
Yes.
And I see it in the link documents and I
will navigate it to it directly.
What you can see here extra line with a
gel account as we specified it has a
name rounding. Of course you can use the
the numbers if you like and what we can
see amount. Yeah. So now the total is
exactly as as we received and the delta
is posted against defined account.
Looks good.
But wait, here is something else I
wanted to show to you. Salesperson. What
does it says? Andre
looks like me. How does it know that?
Maybe because salesperson is associated
with the customer. We can check it
and we can see that on customer card
there is no salesperson.
All right. Where is this information is
coming from? You already guessed and
correctly guessed that it this
information is coming from Shopify
because it was me who actually
registered this transaction in Shopify
POS.
So we have a new field or new mapping
table which is called staff members
mapping and we can see that employees on
registered on Shopify and how they are
mapped to salesperson. Then if uh any
order which contains information about
stuff uh imported into business central
system will check if there is a
salesperson code and use it instead.
All right.
What else we wanted to explore or talk
about Shopify POS? It will be about
pricing.
Now in Shopify with a new market feature
you can create catalog associated to
market which represents POS point of
sales one or all of them in specific
countries or different combinations
means you can have a impact on how you
define pricing but about this one in the
next video.
Uh check links in the description. Thank
you for watching.